{"tossups": [{"question": "The anonymous Untitled 1986 is a sculpture of one of these animals bursting through the roof of an English house. Damien Hirst\u2019s The Physical Impossibility of Death in the Mind of Someone Living consists of a tank of formaldehyde containing one of these animals. One painting of these animals includes stalks of sugar cane and a shirtless black man in a boat, while another shows sailors about to (*) harpoon one in Havana harbor. For 10 points, name these animals who feature in Winslow Homer\u2019s The Gulf Stream and with \u201cWatson\u201d in a painting by John Singleton Copley.", "answer": "sharks (prompt on \u201cfish\u201d)", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In a play by this man, an architect named Martin Gray falls in love with a goat named Sylvia. Another play by this man centers around an aging couple who has a conversation with Leslie and Sarah, two human sized lizards, about their children, evolution, and fidelity. In this playwright\u2019s first play, a wealthy publishing executive is interrogated by another man. In that play, Jerry (*) impales himself with the knife he pulled on Peter. In this playwright\u2019s most famous play, George and Martha play \u201cget the guest\u201d and talk about their imaginary son. For ten points, name this playwright of Seascape, The Zoo Story, and Who\u2019s Afraid of Virginia Woolf?", "answer": "Edward Albee III", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In a derivation of this condition, a mass gap is realized in the spectrum to avoid the absurd condition in which the addition of particles does not alter the particle density. This condition results when the interparticle distance approaches the thermal de Broglie wavelength of the particles in the ensemble. The fermionic (*) analogue to this phenomenon results from the interactions between electronic and nuclear spins and was first realized by Deborah Jin. For ten points, name this state of matter first observed by Eric Cornell and Carl Wieman, a condition in which the particles of a system collapse to the ground state at low temperatures.", "answer": "Bose\u2013Einstein condensate (accept BEC)", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The antagonist of this film purchases a Pur\u00e9pecha statue at auction. The main character of this movie is interrogated at the home of diplomat Lester Townsend who is later killed by a throwing knife. This film ends with a suggestive shot of a train entering a tunnel right after the protagonist has escaped the henchmen of Philip (*) Vandamm. In this film, Cary Grant stars as Roger Thornhill who in one scene is nearly killed by a crop duster. For 10 points, name this 1959 Alfred Hitchcock thriller which ends with a dramatic chase through Mount Rushmore.", "answer": "North by Northwest", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "This leader served as the Minister of Information and Broadcasting during the Shastri government. The Shah Commission investigated alleged abuses of power by this leader, including the Turkmen Gate Incident and forced sterilizations. To escape an electioneering conviction, this leader ruled through executive decree during the (*) \u201cEmergency\u201d. This leader oversaw the Smiling Buddha nuclear tests, and ordered an attack on the Golden Temple at Amritsar which precipitated this woman\u2019s assassination by her Sikh bodyguards. For 10 points, name this daughter of Jawaharlal Nehru, the 1st female prime minister of India.", "answer": "Indira Gandhi (prompt on \u201cGandhi\u201d)", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This region\u2019s critical frequency is equal to the sine of the angle of attack times the maximum usable frequency. Schumann resonances occur in this region. AEROS and HAARP studied this region, whose polar cap absorption accompanies a release of high-energy protons. The winter anomaly occurs in part of the (*) Appleton-Barnett layer, the densest point of this region. Sporadic-E propagation in this region bounces radio waves off small clouds of gas and geomagnetic storms in Earth\u2019s magnetosphere cause the northern lights, which are visible in this region. For 10 points, name this layer of the thermosphere with many charged particles.", "answer": "ionosphere (prompt on \u201cthermosphere\u201d)", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A bureaucrat in this country denounced two homosexual lions as being afflicted by \u201cdemonic spirits.\u201d This country\u2019s Nakumatt supermarket became the largest in Africa until its sudden bankruptcy in October 2017. This nation\u2019s Deputy President William Ruto avoided a July 2017 assassination attempt while the murder of Christopher Msando sparked controversy before this country\u2019s 2017 (*) presidential election. In that race, Raila Odinga lost at the polls but successfully challenged the legitimacy of incumbent President Uhuru Kenyatta\u2019s victory. For ten points, name this populous East African nation with capital at Nairobi.", "answer": "Republic of Kenya", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This man rose to prominence after winning a Supreme Court case against the Comberland Telephone and Telegraph Company. This man earned a governorship by defeating the \u201cOld Regulars\u201d political machine, and he advanced the careers of O.K. Allen and Alvin King. This ally of Father Charles Coughlin promoted socialist reforms in his (*) Share the Wealth campaign which promised to make \u201cevery man a king.\u201d Assassinated by Carl Weiss in 1935, this politician was fictionalized as Willie Stark in All the King\u2019s Men. For ten points, name this autocratic Louisiana politician nicknamed \u201cThe Kingfish.\u201d", "answer": "Huey Long", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One character in this work says that the second pipe is never as sweet as the first one, and another turns down a black radish. This work begins with a character struggling with his boots and eventually forgetting them at the end of Act One. In this play, one character is commanded to dance and then to (*) think. That character is the slave Lucky, who is being driven by Pozzo. The two protagonists of this play discuss hanging themselves from the solitary tree, but then decide to wait for the word of a man who never appears. For ten points name this play about Vladimir and Estragon by Samuel Beckett.", "answer": "Waiting for Godot", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One composer from this country included \u201cThe Noon Witch\u201d and \u201cThe Wild Dove\u201d in a set of mythological symphonic poems. The \u201cSokol Fanfare\u201d is part of a work written for this country\u2019s military entitled Sinfonietta, while a shrieking high-E depicts the deafness of a man from this country at the end of the quartet (*) \u201cFrom My Life\u201d. The composer of that piece wrote an opera where Kecal agrees to pay 300 florins for Marenka, and another man from this nation used spirituals in a symphony inspired by a trip to America. For 10 points, name this country home to composers like Bedrich Smetana and Antonin Dvorak.", "answer": "Czech Republic (or Czechoslovakia) HALFTIME", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s ship was unable to sail after he claimed to be a better hunter than Artemis. This man killed the husband of his future wife, a daughter of King Tyndareos, while his brother wed her sister. After the death of his father Atreaus, this man returned to his home of (*) Mycenae to reclaim the throne. This man was often at odds with Achilles, and he was killed by his wife Clytemnestra and her lover Aegisthus after sacrificing his daughter Iphigenia to the gods. For 10 points, name this man who led the Greeks in the Trojan War.", "answer": "Agamemnon", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "A process associated with this trait is found in plants such as Eastern skunk cabbage and Voodoo lily. That process occurs in brown adipose tissue and dissipates the energy generated by the proton motive force. A few large reptiles display this trait, which was most famously documented in a female Burmese python. (*) Countercurrent exchange is a hallmark of this trait. Organisms that display this trait are the only ones that can generate a fever, and this trait allows animals to thrive in polar climates. For ten points, name this trait exhibited in mammals and birds that allows them to regulate their internal body temperature.", "answer": "endothermy (accept homeotherm, accept warm-blooded)", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Section 42 of a poem by this writer says \u201cHis voice in all her music, from the moan\u201d and says that the soul of the title figure \u201cbeacons from the abode where the Eternal are.\u201d Another poem by this writer says to the title figure, \u201cTeach me half the gladness / That thy brain must know,\u201d and (*) \u201cHail to thee, blithe Spirit!\u201d This poet also wrote that \u201cTwo vast and trunkless legs of stone / Stand in the desert\u201d in a poem whose title figure says to \u201cLook on my Works, ye Mighty, and despair!\u201d For ten points, name this poet of Adona\u00efs, \u201cTo a Skylark,\u201d and \u201cOzymandias.\u201d", "answer": "Percy Bysshe Shelley", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This kingdom repulsed a Swedish invasion during the Great Sleigh Drive. This kingdom won the Battles of Fehrbellin and Chotusitz, and awards issued by its army include the Pour le M\u00e9rite and the Iron Cross. Napoleon crushed this kingdom at the Battle of Jena, but it later assisted in Napoleon\u2019s defeat at (*) Leipzig. In the mid-nineteenth century, Helmuth von Moltke the Elder led this kingdom\u2019s military to victory over Denmark and Austria. For ten points, name this unifying German kingdom of Frederick the Great and Otto von Bismarck which won a namesake war against France.", "answer": "Kingdom of Prussia (prompt on \u201cGermany\u201d)", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "According to John Locke, this condition is a state of conflict between a conqueror with absolute power and the conquered. Rousseau posited that this condition only persists because people fear physical harm while Montesquieu linked it to hotter climates. A person of this condition in Plato\u2019s Meno helps prove a point about knowledge by solving a (*) geometry problem. This condition names half of a dialectic described in Hegel\u2019s Phenomenology of Spirit which compares lordship and bondage. For ten points, name this condition of forced servitude in which one human being is owned by another.", "answer": "slavery (prompt on \u201cbondage\u201d until mentioned)", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "The Makgadikgadi [mack-gah-deek-gah-DEE] Salt Pan covers nearly 2,000 miles of this desert, which takes its name from a Tswana word meaning \u201cgreat thirst.\u201d One tribe from this desert uses the Diamphidia beetle to make poison arrows, and this desert\u2019s only permanent river is the Okavango. The film The Gods Must Be Crazy is set in this desert, where for centuries the (*) San people, also known as the Bushmen, have spoken a language known for its clicking sounds. For ten points, name this desert which covers much of Southern Africa, including Namibia, South Africa, and Botswana.", "answer": "Kalahari Desert", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "This author wrote many poems about love including \u201cMakeup for a Woman\u2019s Face\u201d. This author was exiled to Tomi, a town along the Black Sea, for reasons he described as a \u201cpoem and a mistake,\u201d most likely one of those in his Ars Amatoria. He\u2019s not Homer, but (*) Penelope begs Odysseus to come home to Ithaca in a work by this author, and in another Sappho speaks to her lover Phaon. Those works are found in the collection \u201cThe Heroides.\u201d Another collection by this author focuses on the changes of mythological characters. For ten points, name this author of The Metamorphoses.", "answer": "Publius Ovidius Naso", "subcategory": "Classical Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The equivalent of this practice in Sikhism is called Amrit Sanchar or Khande di Pahul. The Zoroastrian equivalent of this practice is Navjote, during which one begins to wear the Sudreh and Kusti. Marcionism allowed for this action to be performed on the dead, a process which is also done by many (*) Mormons. The Christian version of this practice originated with tevilah, a Jewish purification rite, and is generally modeled on John\u2019s performance of this action on Christ. For 10 points, name this religious sacrament in which a person is initiated into Christianity by washing away original sin with water.", "answer": "baptism (prompt on \u2018initiation\u2019 until mentioned)", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "One form of this technique uses the transfer of spin-polarization via cross-relaxation, the nuclear Overhauser effect. Another variety of this technique that relies on inelastic scattering employs notch or edge filters. That version involves a Stokes or anti-Stokes shift and is named for (*) Raman. The result of this technique can be plotted on a wavenumber vs. transmittance graph, which peaks between 3700 and 3200 inverse centimeters in the presence of terminal alkynes or amides. For 10 points, name this method of analyzing compounds that comes in NMR and infrared forms.", "answer": "spectroscopy", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Early references to this city are found in the Execration Texts and the Amarna Letters. The Hasmonean Kingdom was centered around this city, from which the historian Josephus hailed, and the Well of Souls is found in this city. Aelia Capitolina was constructed on top of the ruins of this city, which was (*) sacked by the Romans in 70 AD. The largest Crusader kingdom was named for this city, though it was later reconquered by Saladin. For ten points, name this disputed Israeli capital, a holy city in Islam, Christianity, and Judaism.", "answer": "Jerusalem", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "As his last act in one office, this man vetoed the Bonus Bill. This Princeton grad and owner of Paul Jennings helped write the Virginia Statute for Religious Freedom and staunchly opposed Macon\u2019s Bill Number 2. This man wrote the original version of the 27th (*) Amendment, and as president this man temporarily governed from Brookeville, Maryland after the Battle of Bladensburg. With John Jay and Alexander Hamilton, this man authored The Federalist Papers. For ten points, name this \u201cFather of the Constitution\u201d who led the United States during the War of 1812 as the nation\u2019s fourth president.", "answer": "James Madison Bonuses", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "This storm inspired Kanye West to remark that \u201cGeorge Bush doesn\u2019t care about black people.\u201d For ten points each:", "answers": ["Hurricane Katrina", "Louisiana Superdome (accept Mercedes Benz Superdome)", "Michael D. Brown"], "parts": ["Name this 2005 hurricane which brought massive destruction to the American Deep South, especially in New Orleans\u2019 Ninth Ward.", "During Hurricane Katrina, up to 20,000 New Orleans residents who could not leave the city gathered in this stadium, often in squalid and dangerous conditions. This stadium is home to the New Orleans Saints.", "This Director of FEMA during Hurricane Katrina was heavily criticized for his handling of the crisis, though President Bush notoriously stated that this man was doing a \u201checkuva job.\u201d"], "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "This pair used a mosquito to correctly identify the lords of Xibalba among a group of mannequins. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Hero Twins", "Mayan Civilization", "the Bacabs"], "parts": ["Name this pair that survived the Dark House before allowing the Xibalbans to win a ballgame. Their real names are Hunahpu and Xbalanque.", "The Hero Twins feature in the mythology of this Mesoamerican civilization whose tales are recorded in the Popul Vuh.", "These four deities, who are thought to be the sons of the supreme deity Itzamn\u00e1, represent the four cardinal directions and hold up the sky."], "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "In this novel, the protagonist makes a living by embroidering clothing although she is cast out of society. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Scarlet Letter", "\u201cRappaccini's Daughter\u201d", "\u201cThe Minister\u2019s Black Veil\u201d"], "parts": ["Name this Nathaniel Hawthorne novel about Hester Prynne and her daughter Pearl, titled after a mark on Hester\u2019s clothing.", "In this short story by Hawthorne, a poisonous girl dies after taking an antidote given to her by her lover. This story is named for the child of a reclusive Italian scientist", "This other short story by Hawthorne opens with a sexton ringing a bell and sees Mr. Hopper wear the title garment."], "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about spectrophotometry. For ten points each:", "answers": ["ultraviolet (accept UV)", "Beer\u2019s law (accept Beer\u2013Lambert\u2013Bouguer law)", "no unit (accept unitless or equivalents, accept arbitrary units, prompt on \u201cAU\u201d)"], "parts": ["Early spectrophotometers did not work in this range of electromagnetic radiation with wavelength from 10 to 400 nanometers. Its wavelength is longer than x-rays but shorter than visible light.", "This law of spectrophotometry relates the transmittance and absorption to the path length of the beam of light. It is stated as A equals abc or A equals path length times concentration times epsilon, the extinction coefficient.", "Absorbance is measured in this unit because it is the base ten logarithm of the ratio of transmitted and received radiant flux. Relative density is also measured by this unit."], "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This football player played second base in Minor League Baseball after being drafted by the Colorado Rockies. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Russell Wilson", "Seattle Seahawks", "Malcolm Butler"], "parts": ["Name this NFL quarterback from the University of Wisconsin who became the second black quarterback to win a Super Bowl after defeating the Denver Broncos in Super Bowl XLVIII.", "Wilson plays for this west coast team coached by Pete Carroll. This team\u2019s fans are known as the \u201c12th Man\u201d and hold the world record for loudest crowd noise at a sporting event.", "The Seahawks lost Super Bowl XLIX to the New England Patriots after Wilson threw an interception to this New England cornerback with 20 seconds left in the game."], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "The Troodos Mountains carve out one side of this island\u2019s northern Mesaoria plain. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Cyprus", "Turkey", "The United Kingdom (accept Great Britain)"], "parts": ["Name this Mediterranean island once led by Makarios III and with capital at Nicosia.", "The Green Line divides control of Cyprus between the Republic of Cyprus and an unrecognized country established by this nation. This nation invaded Cyprus in 1974 to prevent a union with Greece.", "According to the London-Z\u00fcrich Agreements which created an independent Cyprus, this country was allowed to maintain sovereignty over its Cypriot military installations at Akrotiri and Dhekelia."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Lachlan Macquarie arrived to restore stable British government following this event. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Rum Rebellion", "Australia", "William Bligh"], "parts": ["Name this 1808 rebellion in which army officers took control of New South Wales, allegedly because of a dispute over a certain alcoholic beverage.", "The Rum Rebellion occurred in and around Sydney, the largest city in this country.", "This man was the British governor deposed in the Rum Rebellion. Almost 20 years earlier, this was similarly overthrown by Fletcher Christian in the mutiny on the Bounty."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "One form of this process is described by the Klein\u2013Nishina formula. For ten points each:", "answers": ["scattering (accept Compton scattering or Rayleigh scattering)", "Mie scattering", "Peter Debye"], "parts": ["Name this process in which electromagnetic radiation is diffused or deflected. The \u201cRayleigh\u201d type of this process is responsible for the blue sky.", "This form of scattering, named for a German physicist, can be used to explain the color of gold nanoparticles suspended in water. This form of scattering is not very dependent on wavelength.", "The Mie solution is also named for Lorenz and this scientist, who created the T cubed model of heat capacity. He also names the unit of electric dipole moment."], "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This man painted two widely-panned landscapes of <em>Ovid among the Scythians</em>. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Eug\u00e8ne Delacroix", "Lady Liberty", "Death of Sardanapalus"], "parts": ["Name this French romantic painter of many works depicting the Greek War of Independence like Massacre at Chios and Greece Expiring on the Ruins of Missolonghi.", "Delacroix\u2019s best known work depicts this lady \u201cleading the people\u201d during the July revolution. This figure stands next to a young boy waving a tricolor flag and wearing a Phrygian cap.", "In this other Delacroix painting, an indifferent king lounges on a red bed while his concubines are slaughtered."], "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about important people in linguistics. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Noam Chomsky", "B.F. Skinner", "Edward Sapir"], "parts": ["This MIT professor and left-wing thinker proposed the idea of universal grammar and coined the phrase \"colorless green ideas sleep furiously\" as a grammatically correct but nonsensical sentence.", "In one work, Chomsky ridiculed the linguistic ideas of Beyond Freedom and Dignity and Verbal Behavior, both of which were written by this American psychologist and pioneer of operant conditioning.", "Though their namesake term is a misnomer, this man and Benjamin Lee Whorf name a hypothesis which asserts that language shapes how people think of and judge the world."], "category": "Social Science"}, {"leadin": "John of Gaunt fled to Scotland to escape this event. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Peasants\u2019 Revolt (or the Great Rising)", "Walter \u201cWat\u201d Tyler", "the Black Death (accept Black Plague, prompt on \u201cbubonic plague\u201d)"], "parts": ["Name this major 1381 uprising of the English lower classes against taxes levied by King Richard II.", "The Peasants\u2019 Revolt was led by this man from Kent. Amidst a meeting with the king, this man drew the ire of the Mayor of London, who then mortally wounded him in a fight.", "One of the primary causes of the Peasants\u2019 Revolt was this devastating pandemic which killed roughly half of England\u2019s population and greatly raised the value of peasant labor."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "One of this man\u2019s most famous works is an adaptation of Joaquin Rodrigo\u2019s <em>Concierto de Aranjuez</em>. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Miles Davis", "Herbie Hancock", "\u201cCantaloupe Island\u201d"], "parts": ["Name this eminent jazz trumpeter behind albums like Kind of Blue and Sketches of Spain.", "Miles Davis\u2019s Quintet included this pianist and future leader of The Headhunters. This man composed \u201cWatermelon Man\u201d and \u201cChameleon\u201d as well as the soundtrack for Fat Albert.", "Hancock wrote this jazz standard in 1964. This song takes it name from an imaginary melon-themed location."], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "The mitral valve and tricuspid valve are located in this organ. For ten point each:", "answers": ["human heart", "right atrium (prompt on \u201catrium\u201d)", "coronary sinus"], "parts": ["Name this four-chambered organ located between the lungs that pumps blood throughout the body.", "This chamber of the heart is the first to receive deoxygenated blood from the body. It contains the SA node.", "Deoxygenated blood enters the right atrium through the superior vena cava, the inferior vena cava, and this collection of veins which forms a partial circle around the heart."], "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This faith\u2019s two main branches are known as Quanzhen and Zhengyi. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Daoism (or Taoism)", "Lao Tzu (accept Laozi or Lao Tse)", "wu wei"], "parts": ["Name this traditional Chinese faith which encourages adherence to the Three Treasures of compassion, frugality, and humility. This tradition\u2019s namesake concept is known as \u201cthe way.\u201d", "This philosopher and \u201cOld Master\u201d founded Daoism and wrote the Tao Te Ching.", "Lao Tzu and other Daoists value this concept which is often translated as \u201ceffortless action.\u201d People who embrace this concept exist in harmony with nature."], "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "Ayatollah Khomeini placed a bounty on this man\u2019s head after the publication of his most famous work. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Salman Rushdie", "The Satanic Verses", "drowning (accept walking into the sea and equivalents)"], "parts": ["Name this Indian British author who wrote works like Shame, Grimus, and Midnight\u2019s Children.", "In this highly controversial Rushdie novel, Gibreel Farishta and Saladin Chamcha fall from a plane crash and turn into the archangel Gabriel and the devil, respectively.", "In the section of The Satanic Verses called \u201cAyesha\u2019s Dream,\u201d all of the followers of Ayesha die by this method."], "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "The Ackermann function uses this concept. For ten points each:", "answers": ["recursion (accept recursive or recursive function)", "mergesort (or merge sort)", "stability (accept stable)"], "parts": ["Name this computing concept in which a function calls itself. The factorial function uses this concept.", "This sorting algorithm recursively divides the inputted list into sublists of length 1, and then orders and combines the sublists. This algorithm was invented by John von Neumann in 1945.", "Mergesort is usually implemented as a sort with this property, meaning identical elements in a list will remain in their original order. Quicksort generally does not possess this property."], "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "One side used the reverse slope defense to great effect in this battle. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Battle of Waterloo", "Arthur Wellesley, 1st Duke of Wellington (accept either)", "Gebhard Leberecht von Bl\u00fccher"], "parts": ["Name this 1815 battle in Belgium, the final clash of the Napoleonic Wars. This decisive Allied victory led to the final defeat and exile of Napoleon.", "This British General commanded Allied forces at Waterloo. Earlier in his career, this man led Anglo-Spanish troops in the Peninsular War.", "The Duke of Wellington received timely assistance from this eccentric Prussian general. Two years before Waterloo, this man temporarily believed he was pregnant with an elephant."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Outlaws make great literary characters. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Robin Hood", "Sir Walter Scott", "True History of the Kelly Gang"], "parts": ["This outlaw lives in Sherwood Forest and steals from the rich and gives to the poor. This highly skilled archer was satirized by the Mel Brooks film Men in Tights.", "This author of Waverly and The Heart of Midlothian wrote about a dashing Scottish outlaw named Rob Roy.", "This work by Peter Carey follows an Australian outlaw as he robs banks and takes over towns."], "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "A \u201cfull\u201d piece of this type includes a Kyrie, a Gloria, a Credo, a Sanctus, and an Agnus Dei. For ten points each:", "answers": ["mass", "Giovanni Pierluigi da Palestrina", "timpani (accept kettle drum, prompt on \u201cdrum\u201d)"], "parts": ["Name this choral genre. Pieces in this genre are often sung in Latin from the Eucharistic Liturgy.", "This composer, who pioneered polyphonic sacred music, is known for his Pope Marcellus Mass.", "Haydn\u2019s Missa in Tempore Belli, or mass in the time of war, is also known as \u201cPaukenmesse\u201d for its dramatic use of this percussion instrument."], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "In this novel, the title character gains entry into a section of the Army of the North under General Arroyo by shooting a hole through a silver peso. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Old Gringo", "Carlos Fuentes", "soldiers"], "parts": ["Name this novel about Ambrose Bierce\u2019s death during the Mexican Revolution.", "This author wrote The Old Gringo and The Death of Artemio Cruz.", "Fuentes chose to include Ambrose Bierce in his novel because of his admiration for an anthology by Bierce named for these people \u201cand civilians\u201d. The Things They Carried is a novel about these people in Vietnam."], "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "After the death of the protagonist of this novel, one of his former lovers kisses the lips of his severed head, as her ancestor, Queen Margot, did. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Red and the Black (accept Le Rouge et Le Noir)", "Stendhal (accept Marie-Henri Beyle)", "The Pink and the Green"], "parts": ["Name this novel titled for the tension between the clerical and secular interests of Julien Sorel.", "This author wrote The Red and the Black as well as The Charterhouse of Parma.", "This unfinished Stendhal novel about Mina Wanghen follows a similar naming format to The Red and the Black."], "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}]}